The shocking police crackdown on protestors in Ferguson, Missouri,
إن القمع الفظيع الذي مارسته الشرطة ضد المتظاهرين في فيرغسون، ميزوري،
in the wake of the police shooting of Michael Brown,
في أعقاب إطلاق الشرطة النار على مايكل براون،
underscored the extent to which advanced military weapons and equipment,
أكدَّ على مدى تقدم الأسلحة والمعدات العسكرية
designed for the battlefield,
المصممة للاستخدام في أرض المعركة،
are making their way
في كونها تشق طريقها
to small-town police departments across the United States.
إلى أقسام شرطة البلدات الصغيرات في أرجاء الولايات المتحدة.
Although much tougher to observe,
وعلى الرغم من صعوبة ملاحظته،
this same thing is happening with surveillance equipment.
فإن الأمر نفسه يحدث مع أجهزة المراقبة.
NSA-style mass surveillance is enabling
تُمَكِن مراقبة الجمهور على غرار ناسا
local police departments to gather vast quantities
اقسام الشرطة المحلية من تجميع كميات كبيرة
of sensitive information about each and every one of us
من المعلومات الحساسة عن كل واحدٍ منا،
in a way that was never previously possible.
بطريقة لم تكن ممكنة أبدًا في السابق.
Location information can be very sensitive.
معلومات الموقع من الممكن أن تكون حساسة جدًا.
If you drive your car around the United States,
إذا قمت بقيادة سيارتك في نواحي الولايات المتحدة،
it can reveal if you go to a therapist,
بإمكانها أن تكشف فيما إذا كنت تذهب إلى الطبيب
attend an Alcoholics Anonymous meeting,
أو تحضر اجتماعًا لمدمني كحول مجهولين،
if you go to church or if you don't go to church.
إذا كنت تذهب إلى الكنيسة أو لا تذهب.
And when that information about you
وعندما تُجمع هذه المعلومات عنك
is combined with the same information about everyone else,
مع نفس المعلومات عن كل شخص آخر،
the government can gain a detailed portrait
تستطيع الحكومة تحصل على وصف مُفَصَل
of how private citizens interact.
لكيفية تفاعل المواطنين العاديين.
This information used to be private.
اعتادت هذه المعلومات أن تكون سرية.
Thanks to modern technology,
وبفضل التقنيات الحديثة،
the government knows far too much about what happens behind closed doors.
تعلم الحكومة أكثر بكثير عما يحدث خلف الأبواب الموصدة.
And local police departments make decisions about who they think you are
وتتخذ دوائر الشرطة المحلية قرارات بشأن ما يعتقدونه عنك
based on this information.
بناءً على هذه المعلومات.
One of the key technologies driving mass location tracking
وإحدى التقنيات الرئيسية التي تقود رصد مواقع الجمهور
is the innocuous-sounding Automatic License Plate Reader.
هو رادار لوحة الأرقام الأوتوماتيكي ذو الملامح السلمية.
If you haven't seen one,
إذا لم ترَ واحدًا،
it's probably because you didn't know what to look for --
فإنه من المحتمل لأنك لم تعلم ما الذي تبحث عنه --
they're everywhere.
إنها في كل مكان.
Mounted on roads or on police cars,
مركبة على الطرق أو على سيارات الشرطة،
Automatic License Plate Readers capture images of every passing car
تلتقط رادارات لوحة الأرقام الأوتوماتيكية صورًا لكل السيارات المارة
and convert the license plate into machine-readable text
وتحوِّل لوحة الأرقام إلى نص مقروء آليًا
so that they can be checked against hot lists
حتى يمكن مقارنتها بالقوائم الأشهر
of cars potentially wanted for wrongdoing.
من السيارات التي يحتمل أنها مطلوبة بسبب قيامها بمخالفات.
But more than that, increasingly,
ولكن زيادة على ذلك، على نحو مستمر،
local police departments are keeping records
تحتفظ أقسام الشرطة المحلية بسجلات
not just of people wanted for wrongdoing,
ليس فقط عن الأشخاص المطلوبين لقيامهم بمخالفات،
but of every plate that passes them by,
بل عن كل لوحة تمرعليهم ولا يلاحظوها بتدقيق،
resulting in the collection of mass quantities of data
مما أدى إلى جمع كميات هائلة من البيانات
about where Americans have gone.
عن الأماكن التي ذهب إليها الأمريكيون.
Did you know this was happening?
هل علمتم أن هذا كان يحدث؟
When Mike Katz-Lacabe asked his local police department
عندما طلب (مايك كاتز لاكبي) من قسم الشرطة المحلية التابع له
for information about the plate reader data they had on him,
عن معلومات حول بيانات لوحة الأرقام التي يعرفوها عنه،
this is what they got:
كان هذا ما حصلوا عليه:
in addition to the date, time and location,
بالإضافة إلى التاريخ والوقت والمكان،
the police department had photographs that captured
امتلك قسم الشرطة صورًا اُلتًقِطَت
where he was going and often who he was with.
عن المكان الذي كان يذهب إليه وغالبًا الشخص الذي كان معه.
The second photo from the top is a picture of Mike and his two daughters
الصورة الثانية من الأعلى هي صورة مايك وابنتيه
getting out of their car in their own driveway.
يخرجون من سيارتهم في طريقهم الخاص.
The government has hundreds of photos like this
تمتلك الحكومة مئات الصور كهذه
about Mike going about his daily life.
عن مايك اثناء قيامه بشؤون حياته اليومية.
And if you drive a car in the United States,
ولو قمت بقيادة سيارة في الولايات المتحدة،
I would bet money that they have photographs
أراهنك بالمال أنهم يملكون صورًا
like this of you going about your daily life.
كهذه لك وأنت تقوم بشؤونك اليومية.
Mike hasn't done anything wrong.
لم يفعل مايك أمرًا خاطئًا قط.
Why is it okay that the government is keeping all of this information?
لماذا من العادي بالنسبة للحكومة أن تحتفظ بكل هذه المعلومات؟
The reason it's happening is because,
السبب في وراء حدوث هذا هو لأنّ،
as the cost of storing this data has plummeted,
بينما قد هبطت تكلفة تخزين هذه البيانات،
the police departments simply hang on to it,
تتشبثت ببساطة أقسام الشرطة بها،
just in case it could be useful someday.
فيما لو يمكن أن تكون مفيدة يومًا ما.
The issue is not just that one police department
المسألة ليست فقط أن قسم واحد للشرطة
is gathering this information in isolation
يقوم بجمع المعلومات بشكل منفصل،
or even that multiple police departments are doing it.
أو أن أقسام شرطة متعددة تفعل هذا.
At the same time, the federal government
في الوقت ذاته، تقوم الحكومة الفيدرالية
is collecting all of these individual pots of data,
بجمع كل الكميات الضخمة من المعلومات،
and pooling them together into one vast database
وإشراكها معًا في قاعدة بيانات ضخمة
with hundreds of millions of hits,
بمئات الملايين من الصور،
showing where Americans have traveled.
تظهر المكان الذي سافر إليه الأمريكيون.
This document from the Federal Drug Enforcement Administration,
هذه الوثيقة من الإدارة الفيدرالية لمكافحة المخدرات،
which is one of the agencies primarily interested in this,
وهي إحدى الوكالات الرئيسية المهتمة بالأمر،
is one of several that reveal the existence of this database.
هي واحدة من وثائق كثيرة تكشف وجود قاعدة البيانات هذه.
Meanwhile, in New York City,
في الوقت نفسه، في مدينة نيويورك،
the NYPD has driven police cars equipped with license plate readers
قادت شرطة نيويورك سيارات شرطة مجهزة برادارات لوحة الأرقام
past mosques in order to figure out who is attending.
بجانب المساجد لتعرف من الذي يحضر.
The uses and abuses of this technology aren't limited to the United States.
لا تقتصر استخدامات وانتهاكات هذه التقنية على الولايات المتحدة.
In the U.K., the police department
ففي المملكة المتحدة، وضع قسم الشرطة
put 80-year-old John Kat on a plate reader watch list
(جون كات) -80 عامًا- على قائمة المراقبة للرادار،
after he had attended dozens of lawful political demonstrations
بعد حضوره العشرات من المظاهرات السياسية المرخصة
where he liked to sit on a bench and sketch the attendees.
حيث أحب أن يجلس على مقعد ويرسم الحاضرين.
License plate readers aren't the only mass location tracking technology
إن رادارات لوحة الأرقام ليست تقنيات رصد مواقع الجمهور الوحيدة
available to law enforcement agents today.
المتاحة لموظفي تطبيق القانون اليوم.
Through a technique known as a cell tower dump,
فمن خلال تقنية تسمى مستودع أبراج الاتصالات
law enforcement agents can uncover who was using
يستطيع موظفو تطبيق القانون كشف من كان يستخدم
one or more cell towers at a particular time,
واحد أو أكثر من أبراج الاتصالات في وقت معين،
a technique which has been known to reveal
إنها التقنية التي عُرِفت بأنها تكشف
the location of tens of thousands and even hundreds of thousands of people.
موقع عشرات بل مئات الآلاف من الأشخاص.
Also, using a device known as a StingRay,
أيضاً، عن طريق استخدام جهاز يدعى ستينغري،
law enforcement agents can send tracking signals
يستطيع موظفو تطبيق القانون إرسال إشارات مراقبة
inside people's houses to identify the cell phones located there.
داخل بيوت الناس لتحديد الهواتف الخلوية الموجودة هناك.
And if they don't know which house to target,
وإذا لم يعرفوا أي بيت ليستهدفوه،
they've been known to drive this technology
عُرف عنهم أنهم يذهبون بهذه التقنية
around through whole neighborhoods.
في جميع أنحاء الأحياء السكنية.
Just as the police in Ferguson possess high-tech military weapons and equipment,
كما أن شرطة فيرغسون تمتلك أسلحة ومعدات عسكرية ذات تقنية عالية،
so too do police departments across the United States
ونفس الحال مع أقسام الشرطة في أرجاء الولايات المتحدة
possess high-tech surveillance gear.
إذ تمتلك معدات مراقبة ذات تقنية عالية.
Just because you don't see it,
فقط لأنك لا تراها،
doesn't mean it's not there.
ذلك لا يعني بأنها غير موجودة.
The question is, what should we do about this?
السؤال هو، ما الذي يجب علينا فعله تجاه هذا الأمر؟
I think this poses a serious civil liberties threat.
أعتقد أن هذا يضع خطرًا حقيقيًا على الحريات المدنية.
History has shown that once the police have massive quantities of data,
أظهر التاريخ أنه عندما تملك الشرطة كميات ضخمة من البيانات،
tracking the movements of innocent people,
وتقوم برصد حركات الناس الأبرياء،
it gets abused, maybe for blackmail, maybe for political advantage,
تصبح مُسَتغَلة، ربما للإبتزاز، أو لمكاسب سياسية،
or maybe for simple voyeurism.
أو ربما لنظرة خِلسة بسيطة.
Fortunately, there are steps we can take.
ولحسن الحظ، هناك خطوات يمكننا إتخاذها.
Local police departments can be governed by the city councils,
من الممكن أن تكون أقسام الشرطة محكومة من طرف بلديات المدينة،
which can pass laws requiring the police
والتي من شأنها أن تمرر قوانين تلزم الشرطة
to dispose of the data about innocent people
بالتخلص من المعلومات عن الناس الأبرياء،
while allowing the legitimate uses of the technology to go forward.
بينما تسمح بالاستمرار في الاستخدامات المشروعة للتقنية.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause).
(تصفيق)